[music]
My name is Ashish FM US chief data
analyics officer and I have a
distinguished panel with me today and
we're going to talk about you know
platforms catalog storage which which
sort of like make agents work. Um but in
reality when you start to scale these
things there's some underlying
unglamorous things that most people
don't talk about. So let's see if we can
delve into that from uh the experience
collective experience of this team um on
stage. So let me start by um kicking
things off. Um go ahead and introduce
yourself and tell me about one AI
decision that you've made that's
fundamentally changed how your
organization works. We'll start with
Laurand then Satian and Melissa.
>> Hey, good morning. So, quick intro. I'm
Durantil. I'm one of the founders and
CEO of WA. We actually started WKA 13
years ago and created uh a scalable,
incredibly low latency file system. uh
we didn't predict the GPU, machine
learning, AI, but once we started
actually getting customers into
production even back in 17, most of our
big customers ended up being these crazy
guys with the GPUs. And for a few years
we I we used to tell on board meetings
that it's such a great market we'll take
this detour and eventually we'll go back
and do grown-up uh work and then about 3
years ago the GPT moment happened and
and this is the grown-up work. So uh we
are now uh delivering um many of the
world's biggest uh AI deployment. Each
time Nvidia sells a big GPU cloud,
they're delivering the GPUs and the
network. They need a storage partner to
deliver the storage. And um we we
provide the the most scalable and the
most dense solution. So for the big
projects um our our economics are the
best.
um our decision.
So we've had engineers using
coding agents uh starting about a year
ago or a bit more but then obviously
there was this big inflection around
December January time frame. At that
point we've
transitioned the whole company to use
AI. Um we we put a lot of resource on
every system that we're currently using.
If it doesn't come with its own MCP, we
develop one ourselves. We actually have
the equivalent of what the eye companies
would call for deploy engineers within
our teams. And now we have across
everything HR, finance, go to market
organizations that usually are not
techsavvy.
Um, hundreds of, you know, dashboards,
agents, processes that otherwise would
have required humans but are completely
automated. and it trans transformed
um how how much we can do with the
amount of people we have. Um obviously
it's it's only going to go forward and
something we did recently because we
wanted to control some of the data. Um
some things we connect to claude but
then you have less control and now we
started running our our own GPUs with
our own uh inference and um
and internal MCPs. So for the more uh
sensitive information we can actually
control who has access to what and we
can feel very safe to open absolutely
everything to AI.
>> Um so I'm sadani I'm one of the founders
and the CEO at elation and elation
started in or we started elation in 2012
and 2013 and we were the pioneers in a
space that many people know as data
cataloging. We were the first company to
basically build a data catalog. Um, AI
has been super transformational for us
because if you think about the public
internet, data catalog basically
provides sort of a Wikipedia for data
inside of a company. And so it's a
destination and just like Wikipedia
requires people to come to Wikipedia to
publish articles and to write pros and
equally it requires people to come to
Wikipedia to read that same pros and
description. Um now most people in the
world of the public internet when they
have a question and said to go to claude
or chat GPT or Gemini but they probably
are not directly at least initially
reading the Wikipedia article. And so if
you think about that metaphor that exact
same thing applies in the enterprise we
are big believers that basically every
data transaction whether it's
consumption or even writing of data
ultimately are going to basically be
intermediated by an agent. And so the
result of that if you think that um
agents are basically going to be the
primary consumers of data or at least
intermediate the transactions between
people uh and data you would really
design for agents first and that's
basically what we decided to do 2 years
ago. Uh that has led to a series of
different decisions in terms of how we
think about the architecture how we name
and position the company what we build
and how we build it. But it's been a
massive external transformation and
probably an equally massive internal
transformation in terms of how we think
about the product, how we think about
even um what the interfaces are and what
people use. Um I would say most notably
we ended up buying a company named
number stationation which was founded by
uh a whole set of Stanford PhDs who
basically were doing a lot of early work
on applying transformer models to
structured data and that certainly
helped us advance our capabilities. But
for us it's been a profound shift
because how people acquire knowledge
today is just very different from how
people acquire knowledge you know 3 to 5
years ago. And so, you know, that
reflection has to be true inside the
enterprise just as much as outside.
>> Melissa,
>> awesome. So, I appreciated that you
started by saying this panel is where we
like talk about the stuff that people
don't talk about typically. And I think
as a researcher, so I'm a professor at
Stanford and I study AI in organizations
and um yeah, so I think as a researcher
especially, so I have no P&L, I have
like no revenue. I just get to like get
to meet cool people building cool stuff
and kind of study what's going on.
So in answering the question I was
trying to think of I was thinking of one
of my research sites. So me and my PhD
students will go embed with a company
and sort of watch how AI is being
implemented and like with what impact.
So I was thinking of one of my research
sites. So this is a financial services
institution and I was trying to think of
like a decision that they've made that's
had the most impact on what's going on
in their company. So they decided um to
develop um I was thinking of their most
like mature agentic use case and they're
able to get to about 99% agentic
resolution at this point. There's like
1% of the cases where they're not able
to get to resolution. So what's
affecting them right now is they don't
have um the expertise now. The the
workforce doesn't have the expertise to
go chase out that 1% exceptions where
it's like these gnarly kind of edge
cases that nobody really knows what to
do with. So that's what they're trying
to figure out right now. And then the
other the other piece of the other sort
of challenge that they're facing is that
this has been it's considered so
successful. I mean obviously this is
like a continuing problem for everybody
figuring out what to do with the edge
cases with a workforce that has not done
the simple cases. So um but the second
thing that they're trying to figure out
now so this has been considered a
success. Um the workforce is actually
asking for more. They want more AI. They
want more agentic use cases. Um, so what
the bank is trying to figure out right
now is how to develop like the
organizational muscle memory to just do
this faster to get more buyin across
like legal, HR, compliance where
everyone can kind of sign off on
whatever the use case is so that they
can like stand it up faster. So they
feel sort of stuck around the question
of organizational trust and how you
define that and how you sort of onboard
these sort of use cases.
>> Thank you. I'll I'll stick with you. So
um you spoke about the 1% right? So when
you look at taking an agent from pilot
to production there are certain data
conditions that are obviously
non-negotiable right and uh there's
certain shortcomings which is very
evident once you put one of these things
into production. What do you think
organizations underestimate when they
make sort of these decisions?
>> Yeah. So my answer is like hands down
evals [laughter] like it's actually so I
think what everyone has been surprised
by
cuz so I think when I think when um
companies start out oftent times there's
like this belief that you can have
agents check agents check agents and you
have like all these loops where agents
are checking agents and that can be
powerful but I think what I've seen
companies kind of get surprised by is
that at the bottom of all of those loops
of agents checking agents checking
agents is you have to have a really nice
layer [laughter] of like verif ified
typically human created data of EVLs.
Um, and it's really hard actually to
create EVELs. It's really hard to define
success in a way that humans can then
apply it well enough so that you have
this like nice ground truth data. Um,
one of my favorite descriptions of eval
um, so there's this startup called Arise
and I don't mean to make them famous in
this like huge room, but they have this
like YouTube video where they talk about
um, there's this quote by one of their
developers and he has this phrase that I
love when it comes to emails where he
says it's turtles all the way down.
Turtles all the way down is like loops
upon loops upon loops upon loops of
agents. But then at the bottom you have
to have those emails and they're hard to
define. They're hard to do. Um, I mean
people hate doing it. It's tedious. It's
hard. So I'm curious if the other
panelists have that but that would be my
answer.
>> Saution um I'll add something for you to
answer right. So most people forget that
AI is in a substrate right hardware up
there are certain components of the
architecture with that grounding given
you said a relation like what what do
you think people underestimate the most
organizations when they start to look at
the shortcomings of deployment?
Yeah, I think it's that um these apps
are basically uh I mean because they're
stochastic apps the there's consistent
drift and so a typical software
application you test you put in
production it meets the edge cases both
that you've tested it for and at least
it works consistently and predictably
um that's not the case and I think
largely you know yes you have to
generate emails and I think that's a
general minimum condition but then you
have all of this drift the the
underlying data schema drifts. The
underlying context and the business
rules drift. You know, the tools that
you use are they were once the
appropriate tools, then they start to
hang. Why they start to hang, maybe
they're a different version behind. And
so there's a whole bunch of reasons why
these things then go wrong once you've
initially put them into production. Um
and so then then the question becomes,
well, what's the answer to fixing these
things? And and so part of it is that
you have to triage and then that triage
causes for a new eval. But then the
question is well how do I fix the email?
Because if it doesn't meet the you know
if it doesn't meet it doesn't pass then
all of a sudden you're saying well do I
fix the knowledge base? Do I fix the
underlying data? Was it a problem with
data quality? Was it a problem with
access? Was it a problem with the agent
prompt? And so you have all of these
sort of like and so where does the truth
go and once I even figure out where the
truth goes how do I make basically make
sure that it's correct and appropriate
and it applies in the more general case
because you know then the question
becomes well okay if I change the truth
is this globally true or only true for
this particular use case. So there's a
whole bunch of knowledge management
decisions about what container do you
put things in, how do you fix them that
I think are very complicated and as you
deploy AI more and more the complexity
increases even even more.
Lauren.
Yeah. So going back to evil, you know, a
a year ago everyone were were obsessed
with hallucinations.
Um since the rise of the new reasoning
models and the improvements, it's not
hallucinations any any longer, you
rarely would get uh the model to to
invent things essentially because it now
starts with a lot of context at the
beginning uh if it's set correctly. But
when agents become nested, when they
call each other the t turtles all the
way down, um which started from a
completely different uh
>> um
story the problem many times you have
some nested agent that has a completely
different I would still overload the the
word context but it's not context in the
AI it's answering the with different set
of understanding
and and then you get something that if
if you only employ
logic works out but then when you have a
human look at it at the end and
everything needs to connect it's like
completely ridiculous.
So many time when you're deploying a new
workflow,
it's really important to go and
verify that all the stages feed the
right data to the next one and make
sense of uh the results.
That leads me to the next one. Um so
most data catalogs are basically
inventories give or take, right? Um and
not usable context, right? Well, decent
amount of conversation is about how do
you build context from ontologies and
knowledge graphs and things of that
sort. So what must change to make a
catalog agent ready and who owns the
definitions? Satin, I'll start with you.
>> Yeah, I mean ultimately the definitions
have to be owned by the people that have
the greatest level of understanding. Um
and sometimes those are people who have
these traditional roles in data
stewardship and um typically these are
people who live in the business and
understand the business process
reasonably well. But there are technical
roles that have understanding of the
technical systems which are required and
then you've got business roles that have
have understanding of the business
process. Um and then you need sort of
these quasifunctional roles of people
who understand the systems um that sort
of produce the information. And so
ownership is kind of a very I mean it
goes back to this organizational
question because ultimately ownership is
a fundamental fun like there's there's
not re ownership of the process end to
end in an agentic world requires a
technical individual a functional
individual and then somebody who owns
the content and that can be three people
that can be 30 people depending on what
the process is and what sophistication
is. Um I you know cataloges are to your
point inventories and they are but one
piece of the puzzle. know like a catalog
describes what is and you know I have
customers that come to me and say well
you know my catalog is just a massive
mess and agents don't understand it and
it's because your data is a mess and you
know that the catalog is going to
reflect what you know if your map has
like spaghetti all over the place then
your map's just going to show like
that's your reality your your map's just
going to show that fundamental reality
of your systems and so then the question
becomes well how do I build what ought
to be and many people then come along
and say, "Well, I've got to build just
context." But context and isolation is
sort of a silly thing to go after
because like how do you even know you're
done and when do we even get started?
And so really, it just comes down to
what is the application use case that
I'm trying to light up and how do I
effectively make that thing work and how
do I make it work over time? And that's
when you know you have the right amount
of context. these tools, cataloging and
context provisioning, all of that can
help, but you al you have to know where
you're going in order to get an
understanding of whether or not you have
the right outcome. And that comes down
to do I understand the process? Do I
have the right eval and output? Um, and
many people technologically that are
approaching these problems sort of seem
to forget that that is it fundamentally
comes down to what are you trying to do?
>> Lauren, I'll add a flavor of the uh
question to you. Have you ever seen an
ontology being built with AI first
before context is applied to it?
A AI first is uh I think
probably too aspirational because when
we're working with enterprises,
they they have their history. They're
not it's it's never a green field.
Um, so I wouldn't call any of these
projects a AI first cuz the data has
been there. The mess was created for
long long long time. Um, but now many
organizations acknowledge that they need
a completely different approach when
agents access the data. Um, from from
our perspective, a lot of the data is
actually stored on on flesh where
traditionally these things would be on
hard drives cuz humans can white. Uh,
but the agents actually need incredibly
low latency. And once we're transforming
and and making the the upgrades for the
modern world, we're we're able to not
make it AI first, but at least massage
it a little bit and and get it uh up to
date. Uh something I would add that I
think a lot of uh organizations now
start to realize once they get some
results is they also care about um and
this is a bigger difference from a
standard lake or or other system that uh
when you logged in you had security
there. They want to make sure that if
user A launches an agent or user B
launches an agent, these different users
actually have their credentials
uh follow through the whole process
turtles all the way down. Uh and
this is actually difficult because if
you're just launching API call to to
cloud that has access to everything, it
doesn't work. And this is actually a
strong trigger for for many companies
the the large enterprises to actually
bring this infrastructure inhouse so
they can enforce control.
Melissa since you talked about working
with organizations I'll ask you this and
I think Satya was referring to this as
well. So who owns the business
definitions relationships and meta
metadata needed to support these
decisions? Have you seen organizations
outsource it? bring a bunch of
consultants and subject matter advisers
that do it. Have you seen people that do
it well do it in-house? What what have
you seen that you can reflect upon?
So in thinking about this question, I
was remembering so about 5 years ago um
I had created this brand new class. So I
teach at Stanford. I said I had created
this brand new class called managing
data science organizations and it so
this was 2021 and it was like so cutting
edge and I feel like I had covered all
of the like most recent research about
it was traditional machine learning
applied in organizations and across all
of the papers that I studied to get this
class together. The number one predictor
of an effective ML implementation was
actually the relationship between the
data scientists and the domain experts.
like hands down like it wasn't even like
a subtle effect across all of those
studies. So I thought that was really
interesting. So then when so then like
Chad GBT everyone's like now talking
about Genai. So I got really curious
about whether that relationship was
going to hold um the relationship
between like the developers of Genai
products oric products and the domain
experts. I feel like for the last couple
of years I haven't been seeing that too
too much. I think it's like it's early
days and I think it was like domain
experts were like all just getting
licenses but they weren't like building
kind of bespoke uh use cases but I think
now I'm seeing that now I'm seeing that
you need to have um I mean I think I
can't remember who said forward deployed
engineers right so like that's that's
what FDES are like the forward deployed
engineers who have the technical
expertise to actually build the system
they have to go talk to the domain
experts like they have to actually have
enough business context to actually
build closing and um like this class was
showing like 5 years ago. I mean it's
the same thing like neither side can be
successful alone. You have to have the
business context and you have to have
the technical expertise and if that
collaboration doesn't work then your
system is like is like not going to
work. So it's it is a organizational
challenge because the collaboration
between the two actually is like what
matters the most. Who owns it? It kind
of somebody needs to own it but they
just need to collaborate really well
across those groups. I mean you spoke
about something that gets the heart of
speed and you know the the word that
often hear is like you know there's some
magic in AI that'll make it appear
faster right and they keep telling most
organization there is no magic it's hard
work um all right um let's let's talk
about most people that run enterprises
have some version of a lakehouse
a data warehouse a vector data store
name it right some storage where they've
built you know or an operational system
where they've sort of logically linked
domain and entities together to some end
outcome. Right? So, as we start to look
at agent reliability and as we start to
look at the choices for what an agent
should go after and execute, Satin, I'm
going to start with you. I'm sure this
gets debated at Elation. Um, what
changes in the underlying
inframp compute storage when people look
at sort of what's been built over the
years, warehouse, lakehouse, vector
databases?
>> Yeah. I mean I don't you know people
have different application schemas in
order to be able to light up different
types of operational and analytical
workloads and there are advances that
companies are making in lighting up more
efficient querying systems and more
efficient reads and writes and there's a
lot of discussion around for example
iceber table formats rightfully because
it divorces the you know compute from
the storage and obviously that allows
for a greater degree of flexibility and
sovereignty for for companies. But there
is a lot of innovation that's happening
in the comput stack and that continues
to happen in the consu compute stack.
And I think having a lot of religion
from our perspective and at least as
we've seen with customers around any of
these kind of architectures is is
actually pretty damaging because I mean
you know the moment that you have
religion around doing one thing in a
particular way you find that there's
just a new advancement and so being
flexible in your thinking and fitting
the compute paradigm to the to the use
case I think is just as critical in
compute selection as it is in agent
selection. Um, so I don't I don't come
with a lot of we actually don't come and
I think fundamentally don't come with a
lot of religion around how to store
things or which models to use because
ultimately our customers are basically
using all of these things and they're
trying to use all of these things and
and rightfully have different use cases.
And we do find some customers that have,
you know, deep religion around this
stuff. And, you know, our our approach
generally tends to be almost the
opposite of that, which is, you know,
just like different horses for different
courses. Um, I think, by the way, I
mean, you spoke about ontologies before.
We're we're releasing an ontology
product and we are using agents to
create these ontologies. But I think the
limit of all of this work is that all
these knowledge artifacts, whether
they're cataloges or ontologies or which
compute to select, I mean, ultimately,
you want to get to the point. And I
think the promise of agents is that you
get to the point where you can just
declare your intent and ultimately
things happen. And I think that's the
world that we think you need to design
for. Now getting there I think is a lot
of there's a lot to go do to make that
happen. But I think that's the challenge
in front of us and I think you know any
entrepreneurs and innovators in the
room.
>> Lon your uh your thoughts on this topic.
>> Yeah. So
I I don't think we've we've reached the
level of understanding of where we are
going to be. Um we obviously have a lot
of discussion at WA on how how to look
at these things but
at the
very far end a a warehouse or any SQL
database is is something that was
created for humans
and you have a lot of data engineers and
they design the schemas and you have
other people and and they make sure that
they go through a lot of the content and
they put it there and SQL was created to
allow smart humans to translate other
humans wishes for answers to something
that the current schema can can support.
We have a strong hunch that this is not
the AI native way to hold data for for
the models. These models can hold a lot
more context than what a single human
being can. they can go through the data
a lot quicker. Um
the situation isn't yet stabilized. We
we we've not seen the end result. Um but
you know it was a warehouse, a data
lake, a lakehouse and and we've been
oscillating. Uh I think the end is going
to be a lot closer to going back to a
data lake uh with obviously you you you
need semantic ways of figuring things
out. So everything is going to be uh on
on a vector store. You will have to run
a lot more um you'll run a a a small
agent on the prompt. So we'll do some
massaging on the prompt. It will go
back. It will get some work through the
vector database. It will come back.
Eventually, we'll be able to distill way
more content and data and information
from whatever you have and and it will
be a lot more efficient than anything
we've done before. I cannot give you the
silver board today.
All right. Um we're down to the last 3
minutes or so. We'll take uh questions
from the audience if there's any.
>> You can just start that. Oh yes. And
we'll come to you since Yeah. So I'm
previously on JP Morgan Chase building
scale uh uh lake houses and now I am
actually running my own uh startup conra
building financial air workforce. My
question maybe I'm biased because I've
been 8 years building a pabyte scale big
data systems like you said are we kind
of a leaning all these uh source of
truth context we are talking about the
vector databases and the knowledge
graphs ultimately even I feel that has
to go into a file system and support
that uh uh vector search or the
knowledge search through the file system
I think lance DB is example what do you
guys think uh I think we discuss the
same area but do you us feel that uh it
is a big data problem that we are trying
to solve in a JB Morgan Chase the
biggest issue is the agent how we can
get the data into the agents right so do
you think it is more kind of a big data
problem that we are going in all these
context knowledge graph and the uh data
resolutions
>> by big data you mean um just the size of
the
>> thing like the drift of the data like by
temporarity if today's truth is not the
yesterday's is truth. If he asks agent
to go and uh do something like yesterday
at 10:00, it has to understand that
right. So all these things uh the data
scale-wise is it a big data problem?
>> Van I'll let you take it.
>> Yeah. So I think big big data and you go
back to the concepts of Hadoop and even
Spark and the other systems had these
concept of sharding and shuffling and
getting through and and sifting the data
and you had to design your your queries
and and this still goes back to what I
said earlier that warehouses were
designed for humans. Big data is
designed and
[snorts] and the funnel of the big data
was still designed for old way of of
building uh systems and humans.
I I think end of the day we're going to
be storing as you said closer to a file
system. There is going to be some
semantic search on top of it. Um, true.
We're now seeing other use cases for
also introducing a graph. So, it will be
a combination of vector and graph. Uh,
and we'll we'll end up uh with the
agents just figuring out, hey, this is
the context. These are all of the
content I can get and actually absorb
the the the results out of them.
>> Yeah, we're good. We're sorry, this
thing's flashing at me. So, thank you.
Uh, thank you all of you. I'm sure this
conversation has just started. Thanks a
lot. Thanks.